<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<languages>
    <language name="c">
        <human>C</human>
        <overview>
            C is one of the oldest programming languages of the computer history. It's defined as a high-level programming
            language but however you can embed Assembly code into your program. It's the best choice for writing system
            drivers. It can be also used to write operating system kernels and many more.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Can embed Assembly (and so you can interact directly with the CPU and the hardware)</item>
            <item>Cross-platform</item>
            <item>Fast</item>
            <item>It can also be used to write operating system kernels (Linux is an example) or system drivers</item>
            <item>Native (doesn't have any emulation or virtual machine like Java or Mono C# to be run)</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Cross-platform programs may need some changes in order to be compiled correctly from different compilers</item>
            <item>It's a bit difficult</item>
            <item>Some Assembly knowledge needed to understand and write well-written programs</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="cpp">
        <human>C++</human>
        <overview>
            C++ is an improvement of the C programming language. Unlike C it's an object oriented programming language but
            it implements all C standard features anyway. It can be used to write also operating system kernels and system
            drivers just like C but it has a different linkage.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Easier than C</item>
            <item>Object-oriented, unlike C</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Source linkage changes between different compilers</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="cs">
        <human>C#</human>
        <overview>
            C# is a object oriented programming language developed by Microsoft. It's syntax is very easy but much similar
            to C. It has an extensive set of default libraries and classes which can be used in your own program. Currently
            it's possible to run C# programs also on Linux and MacOS thanks to Mono which is also used by Unity Game Engine.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Cross-platform thanks to Mono (only Mono compiled program are cross-platform)</item>
            <item>Easy to code</item>
            <item>Lots of integrated libraries</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Cross-platform is not native. To run C# Cross-Platform programs you need to install the Mono Runtime module</item>
            <item>Not very fast with Mono</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="html">
        <human>HTML</human>
        <overview>
            First of all, it isn't actually a programming language. It's a markup language. Hypertext Markup Language (commonly
            abbreviated as HTML) is the standard markup language used to create webpages. Web browsers render HTML files into
            visible and viewable webpages. CSS was released four years after the HTML. If you're going to learn HTML, CSS is
            a highly recommended extra, your webpages will look a lot less plain.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Consistency throughout, HTML can be found almost everywhere on the Web</item>
            <item>Many built-in tags</item>
            <item>Neater code, naming convention gives developers easier understanding of what does what</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Only modern browsers support HTML5, this knocks HTML5 out for older ones</item>
            <item>Time-consuming, due to inefficiency of maintaining a pure static HTML website</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="java">
        <human>Java</human>
        <overview>
            Java is everywhere, literally. It's a general purpose language, meaning that you can use it for any kind of
            development. It's actually one of the most used programming languages in the world. Java is derived from C and C++,
            initially developed in 1995 at Sun Microsystems. You can find Java almost anywhere nowadays.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Built-in garbage collection, automatically throws away objects not being used anymore</item>
            <item>Has a very large built-in standard library</item>
            <item>Syntax is similar to that of C++, except it's more simplified</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Development takes more time compared to other languages (e.g. PHP, Python, Ruby)</item>
            <item>Strict with everything (may be a good thing to certain people)</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="javascript">
        <human>JavaScript</human>
        <overview>
            JavaScript is one of the core technologies in producing content for the World Wide Web. It first appeared in 1995,
            and is still widely used today. The language is imperative and structured, dynamically-typed, and object-oriented.
            It can also be used to create server-side applications, if you know what Node.js is.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Executed on the client side, which means you don't have to worry about your server being overworked</item>
            <item>Easy to pickup, syntax is similar to the English language</item>
            <item>Webpages can be easily extended</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Can be easily exploited by malicious users</item>
            <item>Rendered differently throughout different browsers</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="lua">
        <human>Lua</human>
        <overview></overview>
        <pros></pros>
        <cons></cons>
    </language>
    <language name="php">
        <human>PHP</human>
        <overview>
            PHP is a server-side scripting language made for web development, but can also be used for many other purposes. It
            was made in 1994, initially PHP was an acronym that stood for Personal Home Pages. It now stands for PHP: Hypertext
            Preprocessor. Can be embedded into HTML.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Easy-to-use scripting language (for servers and task automation)</item>
            <item>Relatively easy to learn, also popular and common</item>
            <item>Similar to the C language, will be easier for programmers that know C</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Function names are inconsistent</item>
            <item>Unpredictable typing system</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="python">
        <human>Python</human>
        <overview>
            Python is a high-level, interpreted, and dynamic scripting language. It focuses on code readability, requiring
            less lines of code to complete tasks when compared to languages like C++ and Java. Python is also widely used,
            from the simplest scripts to industrial applications.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Easily read and written</item>
            <item>Great language to learn as your first programming language</item>
            <item>No need to compile code to run it</item>
            <item>Standard library has mostly everything you'll need</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Currently limited to desktop applications, not used in mobile development</item>
            <item>Security is an issue, if you don't want the source code to be viewed when distributed</item>
            <item>Slower when compared to compiled languages like C++ and Java</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="ruby">
        <human>Ruby</human>
        <overview></overview>
        <pros></pros>
        <cons></cons>
    </language>
    <language name="scratch">
        <human>Scratch</human>
        <overview>
            Scratch is ideal for individuals with very little or no programming experience. It helps you develop the mindset
            of a programmer, and teaches you the basics of programming. Great for beginners of all ages.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Ability to make things you would be able to make with real code</item>
            <item>Beginner-friendly environment</item>
            <item>Simple user interface allows you to start coding instantly</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Limited, only meant as a language to help you grasp programming concepts</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
    <language name="swift">
        <human>Swift</human>
        <overview>
            Swift is a programming language designed by Apple, for iOS, macOS, watchOS, tvOS, and Linux. It's a general purpose
            language, also a more modern alternative to Objective-C. Swift also draws ideas from many different programming
            languages.
        </overview>
        <pros>
            <item>Easier and faster for programmers to learn</item>
            <item>Easy to read and write, shorter code length overall</item>
            <item>Friendly for beginners, compared to Objective-C</item>
        </pros>
        <cons>
            <item>Compatible with only some platforms</item>
            <item>Fast-paced development on the language, many updates bring about large changes</item>
        </cons>
    </language>
</languages>
